Guide to the Liederkranz Collection ca. 1847-1987 MSS.130
Fales Library and Special Collections
Liederkranz Collection
1837-1987
Fales Library and Special Collections
Deutscher Liederkranz der Stadt New York
MSS.130
200 Linear Feet in 208 boxes and 1 flat-file folder
The Liederkranz of the City of New York is an amateur organization, founded in 1847 as a male singing society, that grew to include choruses, an orchestra, a scholarship competition and fund (the Liederkranz Foundation), and a membership "Dedicated to the Promotion of MUSIC and CULTURE." The Liederkranz Collection is comprised of music scores and parts, documents produced by the Liederkranz of the City of New York, and related documents and items that have been obtained by the club since it began in 1847. The bulk of the collection is choral and orchestral scores and parts.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open without restrictions.
Provenance
In December 1999 the Liederkranz of the City of New York donated its library of music scores and parts, Liederkranz Club and Liederkranz Foundation documents, and related materials to NYU.
Arrangement
The subseries of Series I are arranged alphabetically, by composer's name. Where there is no composer's name, the work's title is used. Folders containing groups of miscellaneous incomplete parts/works are found at the end of a series.
Subseries II.B, II.D, II.E, II.F, and II.G are arranged chronologically. Subseries II.C is divided roughly into three parts, with all Liederkranz concert programs first, followed by Liederkranz dramatic production programs, and then all dinner/event programs. Within each of these divisions, the programs are ordered chronologically. Subseries II.A has been arranged alphabetically after the subseries' first item, which is contained in its own box.
The programs of Subseries III.A are separated by organization, and then arranged chronologically. Subseries III.B is arranged chronologically.
Series IV is arranged alphabetically by composer name. The folder number in this series refers to the item number.
Series 5, which is comprised of five items, is ordered as the items would appear if extracted in order from their corresponding place in Series 1 to Series 3.
Series I: Music
Series II: Liederkranz Produced/Obtained Documents/Objects
Series III: Materials Produced by Other Music Associations and Related Organizations
Series IV: Printed Sheet Music, Choral
Oversize - Series IC: Music, Choral
Oversize - Series IIA: Liederkranz Library Documents/Materials
Historical/Biographical Note
On January 9, 1847, twenty-five men of German heritage founded the "Deutscher Liederkranz der Stadt New York," a male singing society that provided a musical and social outlet for German-American men and also sought to perpetuate the tradition of German music, in both the folk and classical traditions.
By 1861, the society was invited to sing with the Philharmonic Society Orchestra, and its performances of Wagner excerpts at the Metropolitan Opera House and in Boston and Philadelphia were among the first performances of Wagner in the United States. The Chorus sang at the World Columbian Exposition in Chicago. Ferrucio Busoni performed piano works at this concert and others on the Liederkranz's tour. Many well-known musicians have collaborated with the Liederkranz, including Jenny Lind, Victor Herbert, Ernestine Schumann-Heink, Raphael Josephi, Lille Lehman, Helen Traubel, and Lauritz Melchior. The Club has also feted Engelbert Humperdinck, Richard Strauss, and Siegfried Wagner. Well-known members of the Liederkranz include Carl Schurz and William Steinway, who acted intermittently as President from 1867 until 1896. Honorary members have included President Theodore Roosevelt, Dr. Walter Damrosch, and Lauritz Melchior.
The Liederkranz has been involved in numerous charitable efforts for the benefit of New York City and its institutions, the Quaker Fund for German Relief, the destitute of the Chicago Fire, etc. The Society established the Liederkranz Foundation, Inc. on April 8, 1948 for the purpose of providing support to young singers and musicians to further their careers.
Scope and Content Note
The Liederkranz Collection is comprised of music scores and parts, Liederkranz Club and Liederkranz Foundation produced documents, and related documents and items that have been obtained by the club since it began in 1847. The bulk of the collection is choral orchestral scores and parts.
SERIES DESCRIPTIONS
SERIES 1: Music
Series I contains music of various instrumentation, as well as libretti for musical works. The bulk of the series is comprised of works for chorus. The series has been divided into the subseries below.
Subseries IA: Manuscript
Contains all music, regardless of instrumentation, and some libretti, that is in manuscript. In instances where a folder of related items (e.g., a set of parts) contained both typoscript and manuscript, the folder has been filed as manuscript.
Subseries IB: Choral Printing Plates
Contains printing plates mounted on wood blocks (with the exception of the work by Türk, folder 50, a plate, unmounted.) The plates are for various four-part choral (TTBB) lieder. All text is in German.
Subseries IC: Choral
Contains printed choral music. Here, this refers to any musical work with chorus. While most of the music here is sheet music (score/parts) for chorus alone, there are some exceptions (e.g., Liszt's "Des Glocken des Strassburger Münsters," which is comprised of a conductor's score and orchestra parts, but no choral parts.)
Subseries ID: Choral Collections
Contains collections of choral music bound together in books. Most of the series is comprised of part books for four-part männerchor.
Subseries IE: Piano-Vocal
Contains music for written, or arranged, for solo voice and piano.
Subseries IF: Lyrics
Contains lyrics without music. This includes lyrics printed as song cards, broadsheets, photocopies, etc.
Subseries IG: Piano
Is comprised of piano music, both solo and duo.
SERIES II: Liederkranz Produced/Obtained Documents/Objects
Subseries IIA: Liederkranz Library Documents / Materials
Contains documents and materials related to the Liederkranz library. The series is mainly comprised of inventories of library holdings.
Subseries IIB: Correspondence
Contains all correspondence to and from the Liederkranz Society, and/or its members. The series has been ordered chronologically.
Subseries IIC: Liederkranz Programs
Contains programs, mainly to concerts and plays, but also to dinners, at which a Liederkranz ensemble might or might not have performed. The series is divided roughly into three parts, with all Liederkranz concert programs first, followed by Liederkranz dramatic production programs, and then all dinner/event programs. Within each of these divisions, the programs are ordered chronologically.
Subseries IID: Letters, Invitations, Memoranda to Liederkranz Members
Includes all documents that would have been given to a Liederkranz member during their membership with the organization. This includes invitations to events, event protocol, meeting minutes, etc. The series has been ordered chronologically.
Subseries IIE: Roll Books
Contains roll books used by Liederkranz Orchestra to track the attendance of its members. The series has been arranged chronologically, with the exception of the last roll book, which is for the 2nd Basses of the Liederkranz Chorus.
Subseries IIF: Liederkranz News[letter]
Contains issues of the "L.K. News," which was the member newsletter of the New York Liederkranz. The series has been ordered chronologically.
Subseries IIG: Miscellanea obtained by the Liederkranz
Contains various items that have somehow been obtained by the Liederkranz. The series has been ordered chronologically.
SERIES III: Materials Produced by Other Music Associations and Related Organizations
Subseries IIIA: Programs
Contains programs of non-LK, or non-LK specific (e.g., The Grand Benefit Concerts) concerts/events.
Subseries IIIB: Miscellanea
Contains miscellaneous items from other (non-LK) music associations and related organizations. This series has been ordered chronologically.
SERIES IV: Printed Sheet Music Collection.
Comprised of the organization's printed sheet music collection.
Separated Material
Unnecessary duplicates of scores and sheet music in the collection have been removed. The duplicates relate to Series IV, Printed Music. Each box is listed below with the boxes from Series IV that they relate to:
Box 1, Liederkranz duplicates, 1-4.
Box 2, Liederkranz duplicates, 5-9.
Box 3, Liederkranz duplicates, 10-17
Box 4, Liederkranz duplicates, 18-21
Box 5, Liederkranz duplicates, 21-22
Box 6, Liederkranz duplicates, 22-25
Box 7, Liederkranz duplicates, 26-28
Box 8, Liederkranz duplicates, 29-32
Box 9, Liederkranz duplicates, 33-36
Box 10, Liederkranz duplicates, 37-39
Box 11, Liederkranz duplicates, 40-43
Box 12, Liederkranz duplicates, 44-47
Box 13, Liederkranz duplicates, 48-52
Box 14, Liederkranz duplicates, 53-57
Box 15, Liederkranz duplicates, 58-62
Box 16, Liederkranz duplicates, 63-65
Box 17, Liederkranz duplicates, 66-69
Box 18, Liederkranz duplicates, 70-72
Box 19, Liederkranz duplicates, 73-76
Box 20, Liederkranz duplicates, 77-82
Box 21, Liederkranz duplicates, 83-89
Box 22, Liederkranz duplicates, 90-94
Box 23, Liederkranz duplicates, 95-98
Box 24, Liederkranz duplicates, 99-112
Box 25, Liederkranz duplicates, 113-116
Box 26, Liederkranz duplicates, 117-122
Box 27, Liederkranz duplicates, 123-127
Box 28, Liederkranz duplicates, 128-134
Box 29, Liederkranz duplicates, 135-136
Box 30, Liederkranz duplicates, 137-141
Box 31, Liederkranz duplicates, 142-149
Box 32, Liederkranz duplicates, 150-156
Box 33, Liederkranz duplicates, 157-161
Box 34, Liederkranz duplicates, 162-163
Box 35, Liederkranz duplicates, 164-165
Box 36, Liederkranz duplicates, 166-167
Box 37, Liederkranz duplicates, 168-169
Box 38, Liederkranz duplicates, 170-171
Box 39, Liederkranz duplicates, 172-173
Box 40, Liederkranz duplicates, 174-175
The following books have been removed from the collection, and now reside in the Fales Library. They have been cataloged individually and are searchable in Bobcat.
Aus ruhmreicher Zeit: Deutsche-amerikanische Dichtungen aus dem ersten Jahre des Weltkrieges, ed. Irving T. Sanders, F.C. Stechert Co., New York, 1915.
Berthold Litzmann, Das deutsche Drama in den litterarischen Bewegungen der Gegerwart: Vorlesungen gehalten an der Universität Bonn, Leipzig, Leopold Voss, 1894.
Frankfurter Evangelisches Gesangbuch, Moritz Diesterweg, Frankfurt am Main, 1886.
Hamerling, Robert, Ahasver in Rom, J.F. Richter, Hamburg, 1885.
Mühlbach, L., ausgewählte Werke, 16 vols., Otto Janke, Berlin 1868.
Spengler, Oswald, Der Untergang des Abendlandes, 2 vols., Beck, München, 1922.
Starck, Johann Friedrich, Tägliches Handbuch in guten und bösen Tagen, Vereinsbuchhandlung, Stuttgart, 1886.
Sybel, Heinrich von, Die begründung des Deutschen Reiches durch Wilhelm I, vol. 6 (of 7), R. Oldenbourg, München, 1894.
Weber, Karl Julius, (here: anonymous), Demokritos, oder, Hinterlassene Papiere eines lachenden Philosophen / von dem Verfasser der "Briefe eines in Deutschland reisenden Deutschen," 12 vols. in 6 books, Hempels Klassiker-Ausgaben, Leipzig, [year].
Werner, Richard, Das Buch von der Deutschen Flotte, Velhagen and Klasing, Bielefeld and Leipzig, 1893
Programs (documents); Sheet music.; Scores.; Songbooks.; Clippings (information artifacts); Scripts (documents); Choral societies |z New York (State) |z New York.; Choral societies |z Germany.; Fliers (printed matter); Choral music.; Music |z New York (State) |z New York |v Periodicals.; German Americans |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York (N.Y.).; German Americans |x Ethnic identity.; Concerts |z New York (State) |z New York |v Programs.; New York (N.Y.) |x Charities.; Opera -- New York (State) New York; World War, 1939-1945 |x German Americans.; World War, 1939-1945 |x War work |x Society of Friends.; Music |x Social aspects.; Music |x Societies, etc. |z New York (State) |z New York |v Periodicals.; Music |x Societies, etc. |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York (N.Y.) |x Buildings, structures, etc. |x Liederkranz Club.; Librettos (documents for music); Lyric sheets.; Invitations.; Parts.; Memorandums.; Music festivals |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Music -- New York (State) -- New York.; Music appreciation.; Music |x Competitions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Correspondence.; Dance cards.; Music |z New York (State) |z New York |x History.; Music |z New York (State) |z New York |x Performance |x History.; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Mendelssohn Glee Club (New York, N.Y.); Arion Society of New York; Carnegie Hall (New York, N.Y.); Liederkranz Foundation; Deutscher Liederkranz der Stadt New York; Deutscher Liederkranz der Stadt New York; Liederkranz Club
- Series I: Music
  - Subseries A: Music – Manuscript
    - [ ], "[ ]," choral (TTBB) score and parts., undated (Box I.A.1, Folder 1)
    - Abt, Franz, "Fünfmalhunderttausend Teufel," score (typo.) and choral parts (manu. and typo.), undated (Box I.A.1, Folder 2)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van, "Meeresstille und glückliche Fahrt," op.112, choral (SATB) parts (Soprano part not present)., undated (Box I.A.1, Folder 3)
    - Beer, Max Josef, "Mailied," op. 33, choral (TTBB) and orch., score and orchestral parts, manu.; choral-piano arr. score, typo., [1887], 1888 (Box I.A.1, Folder 4)
    - Bruch, Max, "Das Feuerkreuz," op. 52, cantata, score for Part I., October 2, 1888 (Box I.A.2, Folder 5)
    - Bruch, Max, "Das Feuerkreuz," op. 52, cantata, score for Part II., October 2, 1888 (Box I.A.2, Folder 6)
    - [arr. by Earle M. Moss], "Deutsche Volkslieder" (for LK Charity Concert, April 1963), soloists, choir, and orch., piano-vocal score, manu. (Box I.A.3, Folder 7)
    - [arr. by Earle M. Moss], "Deutsche Volkslieder" (for Liederkranz Charity Concert, April 1963), soloists, choir, and orch., orch. Parts (high strings), manu. (Box I.A.3, Folder 8A)
    - [arr. by Earle M. Moss], "Deutsche Volkslieder" (for Liederkranz Charity Concert, April 1963), soloists, choir, and orch., orch. Parts (low strings), manu. (Box I.A.3, Folder 8B)
    - [arr. by Earle M. Moss], "Deutsche Volkslieder" (for Liederkranz Charity Concert, April 1963), soloists, choir, and orch., orch. Parts (winds, brass, perc.), manu. (Box I.A.3, Folder 8C)
    - "Deutsche Volkslieder" orchestrations (for Liederkranz Charity Concert, April 1963) (Box 225)
    - [Droske], "Heimatsklaenge," choral score/part., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 9)
    - "Ihr Kinderlein Kommer!" choral (SATB) part/score., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 10)
    - "Jesu, Jesu, schlaf im Stall…" choral (TTBB), parts., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 11)
    - Kunstmann, J.G., "Nachtwächter Weisheit," choral (TTBB) parts, typo. and manu., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 12)
    - Kunz, K.M., "Hymne an Odin," choral (TTBB) parts., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 13)
    - Libretti and role-specific scripts for various operas composed by Hermann Kipper, manu. and typo., ca.1880-1890 (Box I.A.4, Folder 14)
    - Liszt, Franz, arr. by [ ], "Credo," from the "Graner Messe" (or "Missa Solemnis"), [2-piano] reduction (mostly written on two grand staves), score., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 15)
    - Liszt, Franz, "Credo," from the "Graner Messe" (or "Missa Solemnis"), choral parts., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 16)
    - Liszt, Franz, "Credo," from the "Graner Messe" (or "Missa Solemnis"), orch. parts., undated (Box I.A.4, Folder 17)
    - Liszt, Franz, "Die Legende der Heiligen Elisabeth," orchestral parts, manu. (winds, brass) and typo. (strings)., undated (Box I.A.5, Folder 18)
    - Liszt, Franz, arr. for the Liederkranz by Agricol Paur, "Von der Wiege bis zum Grabe," score and orch. parts., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 19)
    - "The Lord is my Shepard," choral, score., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 20)
    - Mania, P., "Der shoenste Wiederspruch," choral (TTBB) part/score., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 21)
    - Marschner, Heinrich August, "Schlachtlied der Sachsen" and "Chor der Normannen" from the opera "Der Templer und die Jüdin," orchestral parts, manu., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 22)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, "Preis dir! Gottheit! (Hymne)," choral (SATB) parts., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 23)
    - Muck, Jacob, "Landsknechts-Scene," score, with small lyric sheet (typo) inserted., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 24)
    - "O Christenheit, sei hocherfreut," choral (TTBB) parts., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 25)
    - "O du Fröhliche!" choral (SATB) part/score., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 26)
    - "O komm, mein Kind, zum Wald hinein," French folksong (SATB), score., undated (Box I.A.6, Folder 27)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, choral (SSAATTBB) parts, SS parts., undated (Box I.A.7, Folder 28A)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, choral (SSAATTBB) parts, AA parts., undated (Box I.A.7, Folder 28B)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, choral (SSAATTBB) parts, TT parts., undated (Box I.A.7, Folder 28C)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, choral (SSAATTBB) parts, BB parts., undated (Box I.A.7, Folder 28)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, score., undated (Box I.A.8, Folder 29)
    - Castelli, J.F., (Schubert), "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, overview of scenes., undated (Box I.A.8, Folder 30)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, vocal parts for roles., Undated (Box I.A.8, Folder 31)
    - Schubert, Franz, [Einlage (insert) zu]"Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, choral (SSAA) parts., undated (Box I.A.8, Folder 32)
    - Schubert, Franz, [Einlage (insert) zu]"Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, orch. parts., undated (Box I.A.8, Folder 33)
    - Schubert, Franz, "Die Verschworenen" (or, "Der häusliche Krieg"), opera, 1st violin orch. part., undated (Box I.A.8, Folder 34)
    - [Vogel] (or [Vogal]), "Walzer," choral (TTBB) parts., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 35)
    - Weber, Bernhard Anselm, "Der Gang nach dem Eisenhammer," orch. and choral parts., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 36)
    - Wenigmann, W., Tannhäuser, oder Die Keilerei auf der Wartburg," operetta, orch. parts., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 37)
    - Wenigmann, W., Tannhäuser, oder Die Keilerei auf der Wartburg," operetta, score., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 38)
    - Wenigmann, W., Tannhäuser, oder Die Keilerei auf der Wartburg," operetta, piano-vocal score., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 39)
    - Wenigmann, W., Tannhäuser, oder Die Keilerei auf der Wartburg," operetta, piano-vocal score., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 40)
    - Wenigmann, W., Tannhäuser, oder Die Keilerei auf der Wartburg," operetta, scripts/synopses, multiple copies, character-specific., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 41)
    - Zöllner, Carl, "Die Deutschen Bundesstaaten, Cantus Memorialis," choral (TTBB) parts and score (typo.)., undated (Box I.A.9, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous incomplete orchestral and choral/orchestral scores, typo. and manu., undated (Box I.A.10, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous orchestral parts, typo. and manu., undated (Box I.A.10, Folder 44A)
    - Miscellaneous orchestral parts, typo. and manu., undated (Box I.A.10, Folder 44B)
  - Subseries B: Music – Choral, Printing Plates
    - Glessmer, Felix, "Schön blüh'n die Heckenrosen," printing plate on wood block, choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.B.11, Folder 45)
    - Hansen, Ernst, "Heimat," op. 264, printing plate on wood block, choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.B.11, Folder 46)
    - [Orth, Ph.], "Nun Abe!", printing plate on wood block, choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.B.11, Folder 47)
    - after Schubert, Franz, "Abendsriednen," printing plate on wood block, choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.B.12, Folder 48)
    - "Das stille Tal," folksong, printing plate on wood block, choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.B.12, Folder 49)
    - Türk, C., "Wie könnt ich bein vergessen. (Mein Lieden)," printing plate, choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.B.12, Folder 50)
  - Subseries C: Music – Choral
    - Bruch, Max, "Das Lied von der Glocke," choir (SATB), solos voices, orchestra, and organ, score., 1879 (Box I.C.13, Folder 51)
    - Liszt, Franz, "Die Glocken des Strassburger Münsters (The Bells of Strasburg Cathedral)," text after Wordsworth, score (first edition)., 1875 (Box I.C.13, Folder 52)
    - Liszt, Franz, "Die Glocken des Strassburger Münsters (The Bells of Strasburg Cathedral)," text after Wordsworth, orchestra parts., 1875 (Box I.C.13, Folder 53)
    - Hiller, Ferdinand, "Saul," op. 80, oratorio, text by Moritz Hartmann, score., undated (Box I.C.14, Folder 54)
    - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, "Lobgesang," op.52, "after the words of the holy writing", symphony-cantata, score., undated (Box I.C.14, Folder 55)
    - Adams, A. Emmett, "The Bells of St. Mary's," choral (SSA) score/part., [1936] (Box I.C.15, Folder 56)
    - Armstrong, Harry, "Nellie Dean," choral (TTBB) score/part., [1969] (Box I.C.15, Folder 57)
    - "Auld Lang Syne," choral (TTB) score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 58)
    - Book of women's choral parts for the Festival Chorus of the "35. National-Saengerfest" of the Nordoestlicher Saengerbund von Amerika," choral (SSAA) score/part., 1964 (Box I.C.15, Folder 59)
    - "Bald gras ich am Neckar" and "Im schönsten Wissengrunde," folksongs, chorus (TB) score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 60)
    - Baldamus, Gustav, "Die Alteweibermühle," op. 91, no. 3, TTBB score and parts., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 61)
    - Brahms, Johannes, "Wiegenlied," choral (TB) score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 62)
    - Brandt, H. Waldesrauschen, choral (SSA) parts., [1941] (Box I.C.15, Folder 63)
    - Carter, Fred, "Where are the Smiles," choral (TTBB) score/part., [1967] (Box I.C.15, Folder 64)
    - Edler, Robert, "In dem Wald," choral (TTBB) score/part., [1951] (Box I.C.15, Folder 65)
    - Four different männerchor pieces published by P.J. Tonger, reference copies, score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 66)
    - Geibel, Adam, "Kentucky Babe (Plantation)," choral (TTBB) score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 67)
    - Gevaert, F.A., "The Emigrants (Die Auswanderer)," choral (TTBB) score and parts., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 68)
    - Haas, Joseph, "Das Jahr im Lied," op. 103, choral (SATB), Tenor and Bass parts., 1952 (Box I.C.15, Folder 69)
    - Handel, George Frideric, "O God, who in Thy Heavenly Hand," choral (SATB) parts., 1979 (Box I.C.15, Folder 70)
    - Herbeck, J., "The Maid in the Valley," choral (TTBB) score/part, mimeograph., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 71)
    - Heun, Hans, "Wanderlied: Frohes Wandern," choral (TTBB) Bass II part., [1956] (Box I.C.15, Folder 72)
    - Hiller, Ferdinand, "Sechs Gesänge," choral (STTBB) parts and 2 scores., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 73)
    - "Hoch! Hoch! Hoch!" choral (TTBB) score., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 74)
    - Hummel, Ferdinand, "Die Rose im Thal," op. 79, choral (TTBB) score and parts., 1902 (Box I.C.15, Folder 75)
    - "I'll Take You Home Again, Kathleen," choral (TTBB) score/part., [1966] (Box I.C.15, Folder 76)
    - "Im Zigeunerlagen," choral (SA) score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 77)
    - "In dulci jubilo," choral score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 78)
    - "Jauchze, mein herz," choral (SATB) score/part., undated (Box I.C.15, Folder 79)
    - Kreutzer, Konradin, "Abendchor" (from the opera "Das Nachtlager von Granada"), choral (SATB) score/part., 1950 (Box I.C.15, Folder 80)